Together forever. Or else.
Fear is a thriller film directed by James Foley.
Nicole Walker always dreamed of being swept away by someone special — someone strong, sexy
and sensitive who would care for her more than anything else in the world.
David is all that and more: a modern-day knight who
charms and seduces her, body and soul.
But her perfect boyfriend is not all he seems to be.
His sweet facade masks a savage, dark side that will soon
transform Nicole's dream into a nightmare.
David McCall, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Nicole Walker, played by Reese Witherspoon.
Steve Walker, played by William Petersen.
Margo Masse, played by Alyssa Milano.
Laura Walker, played by Amy Brenneman.
Logan, played by Tracy Fraim.
Fear is a  1996 American psychological thriller film directed by
James Foley and written by Christopher Crowe.
It stars Mark Wahlberg, Reese Witherspoon, William
Petersen, Alyssa Milano and Amy Brenneman.
The film revolves around the wealthy Walker family whose seemingly perfect life is threatened when teenage daughter Nicole
begins dating David McCall, an attractive and mysterious young man who turns out to be a violent sociopath.
Fear was released by Universal Pictures on April 12, 1996.
The film was largely derided by critics upon its release but became a sleeper
hit in the spring of 1996, grossing $20.8 million at the U.S.
box office against a $6.5 million budget.
It has since become a cult film, while at the same time launching teen idol status for its two young leads –
Wahlberg and Witherspoon – who were romantically linked at the time of the movie's premiere.
Wahlberg was nominated for the MTV Movie Award for Best
Villain at the 1997 MTV Movie Awards.
The film's own producer, Brian Grazer, described it
as "Fatal Attraction for teens".
The film explores themes of psychopath, father, loss of
virginity, teenage girl, psychological thriller.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.